<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-09-22T15:09:34-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2018/09/22/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2018-09-22T12:23:32-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-22T12:23:32-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2018/09/22/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2018/09/22/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Location: Trends in Time and Place</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/location,/gis/2018/08/10/location-trends.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Location: Trends in Time and Place" /><published>2018-08-10T13:14:35-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-10T13:14:35-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/location,/gis/2018/08/10/location-trends</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/location,/gis/2018/08/10/location-trends.html">&lt;p&gt;Location is often dismissed as a way to &lt;strong&gt;‘put something on a map’&lt;/strong&gt; but can we see more than just points on a map? In this talk we will explore methods of extracting location and time trends from data – and plotting that data and extracting meaning for our users beyond just location. We will cover everything from hot-spot analysis vs heat maps to plotting location trends over time and even filtering common locations. We’ll also take a special look at some Google Location History to figure out what types of information we can extract from knowing where a person has been before and what we can predict from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&amp;quot;https://youtu.be/9gAuapWREU4&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;Christopher Moravec speaking at the CSV Conf 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Location is often dismissed as a way to ‘put something on a map’ but can we see more than just points on a map? In this talk we will explore methods of extracting location and time trends from data – and plotting that data and extracting meaning for our users beyond just location. We will cover everything from hot-spot analysis vs heat maps to plotting location trends over time and even filtering common locations. We’ll also take a special look at some Google Location History to figure out what types of information we can extract from knowing where a person has been before and what we can predict from it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Evolution of Esri Software: Esri UC 2018</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/esri,/gis,/machine/learning/2018/08/10/evolution-of-esri-software.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Evolution of Esri Software: Esri UC 2018" /><published>2018-08-10T12:23:32-07:00</published><updated>2018-08-10T12:23:32-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/esri,/gis,/machine/learning/2018/08/10/evolution-of-esri-software</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/esri,/gis,/machine/learning/2018/08/10/evolution-of-esri-software.html">&lt;p&gt;This year was my first time attending the Esri User Conference as a business owner.  I have attended many others in the past, but always as a member of a team and not solely responsible for my company.  I was not overwhelmed by Esri’s display of technology this year, but I was happy about it. Esri seems to have reached a level of maturity in software development where they are working diligently at evolving the software and not making large technological leaps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It still feels like large leaps sometimes as new updates come out several times a year, but this is the expectation we have all placed on software these days.  Whether it is an app on our phone that sends messages to our team or arguably the most complex data platform ever created, we want new features constantly and demand updates of the software providers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;#&quot; alt=&quot;Christopher and Mara at Esri UC&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a small business owner, I am excited to see Esri continuing to evolve software.  And while Esri software is plenty revolutionary, I feel that the current speed of Esri software evolution provides the perfect opportunity for smart, agile companies to bring better solutions to clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are always Esri updates that I believe are more important than others, this year those are: Machine Learning, ArcGIS Enterprise Sites, the Autodesk/Esri Partnership, and Map Girl’s evolution into Map Woman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;machine-learning&quot;&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, by the standard definition of Machine Learning, and not the more “buzz-worthy” one favored by many tech news sites today, Esri has been leading in this space for some time.  Machine Learning is simply put, the application of computer and mathematical techniques to analyze, find patterns, and make predictions. The tools and processes that we have all been using in the ArcGIS platform to better understand our spatial and spatio-temporal data are really advanced machine learning algorithms wrapped up into handy toolboxes.  In the words of Lauren Bennett, Senior Development Team Lead at Esri, “You are all already data scientists, you have been doing this for a while!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;#&quot; alt=&quot;machine learning photo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Esri is also making moves in Deep Learning, especially for object recognition and extraction in aerial imagery, by providing tools to make it easier to cut basemaps into small images for training, and testing.  This is a huge step, as data prep represents a large part of working on these systems. While I was disappointed not to see integration with deep learning toolkits and services, I think Esri is headed in this direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Esri has also been working hard on ArcGIS Insights, which although not directly related to machine learning can be used to quickly understand data, which again is big step in building deep learning systems.  I believe that Esri is poised to play an important role in the democratization of deep learning and artificial intelligence, the question remains though, will they?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&amp;quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Cm_oAaQVWZ8&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;AI and Machine Learning with ArcGIS – 2018 Esri Federal GIS Plenary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&amp;quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KCkGif6wSMo&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;ArcGIS pro 2.3 and Machine Learning from 2018 UC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;arcgis-enterprise-sites&quot;&gt;ArcGIS Enterprise Sites&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the clients that Moravec Labs works with are project based, and that process can make it difficult to manage data by project in ArcGIS Online/Portal.  ArcGIS Enterprise Sites can change that by providing an easy way to configure a “site”, or simple web page, within a Portal to make it easier to manage data and projects.  This is a simple evolution of the platform that will have big impacts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&amp;quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=a0tNPkoXkBg&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;ArcGIS Enterprise Sites – 2018 UC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-autodeskesri-partnership&quot;&gt;The Autodesk/Esri Partnership&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For as long as I can remember, Autodesk and Esri have been rivals, and the usual looser of that rivalry was all of us, the users.  Over time though, things have gotten better, and with this partnership it looks as though Esri and Autodesk are prepared to become a true platform for Building Information Management as well as finally connect Engineers using CAD to Geographic experts.  I am very excited to see where this goes, and how it will benefit our customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;img src=”#” alt”autodesk photo”&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&amp;quot;http://www.esri.com/landing-pages/autodesk-esri-strategic-alliance&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;Autodesk and Esri – ‘Global leaders partnering to drive a more sustainable, resilient future.’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;map-girl-evolving-into-map-woman&quot;&gt;Map Girl evolving into Map Woman&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tech industry has its highs and its lows and its treatment of women and minorities is not normally a shining star; in particular Esri’s use for many years of “Map Girl” instead of “Map Woman” while using “Map Man” seems particularly egregious.  This simple change shows that Esri is starting to think more about inclusivity, and while we all have a long way to go here, this change is progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;#&quot; alt=&quot;map woman&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&amp;quot;http://storymaps.esri.com/stories/2014/WomenInGIS/&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;Storymap of Women in GIS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&amp;quot;https://arcnews.maps.arcgis.com/apps/Cascade/index.html?appid=0e7eb641d1144d60b3c85d07de6b4162&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;MapWoman: The Quest for Insight&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, it was a successful conference for Moravec Labs, meeting other members of the Esri Startup Program, seeing lots of old friends and colleagues and making new ones.  The UC has always been and will probably always be a place for me to learn, meet new people and think about not only the direction of Esri, and now my own company, but also the direction of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Christopher Moravec, August 2018&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This year was my first time attending the Esri User Conference as a business owner. I have attended many others in the past, but always as a member of a team and not solely responsible for my company. I was not overwhelmed by Esri’s display of technology this year, but I was happy about it. Esri seems to have reached a level of maturity in software development where they are working diligently at evolving the software and not making large technological leaps.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Coming up Soon: Esri UC 2018</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/esri,/gis/2018/06/18/esri-uc-coming-up.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coming up Soon: Esri UC 2018" /><published>2018-06-18T01:27:32-07:00</published><updated>2018-06-18T01:27:32-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/esri,/gis/2018/06/18/esri-uc-coming-up</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/esri,/gis/2018/06/18/esri-uc-coming-up.html">&lt;p&gt;We are just weeks away from the 2018 &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;quot;https://www.esri.com/en-us/about/events/uc/overview&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;Esri User Conference&lt;/a&gt; in gorgeous San Diego, California. As a member of the &lt;strong&gt;Esri Startup Program&lt;/strong&gt;, the Esri UC is one of the events we are most excited to attend this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This conference brings together tens of thousands of members of the Esri community from map markers all over the globe. It is a fabulous opportunity to connect with our customers and partners, make new friends, and share the exciting work we’ve been doing at &lt;span style=&quot;color:red&quot;&gt;Moravec&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;color:blue&quot;&gt; Labs&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last year we’ve seen a lot of innovation in the Esri ecosystem and we can’t wait to share our thoughts with you. Here’s some fun little projects we’ve been working on that we’d love to chat with you about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Our new GIS chatbot will help you find the nearest tree to hug or the closest park to meet a friend for lunch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An IoT temperature sensor for the office so you’ll always know whether to bring a sweater or something lighter for swelter summer days.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&amp;quot;https://www.geotools.xyz/&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;GeoTools.xyz&lt;/a&gt; gives you an easy way to do some common GeoDev tasks. For example, Where is that lat/long? or What is the extent of a map if I center it on Portland, OR?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope to see you July 9th in San Diego!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We are just weeks away from the 2018 Esri User Conference in gorgeous San Diego, California. As a member of the Esri Startup Program, the Esri UC is one of the events we are most excited to attend this year.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Using Voice Recognition and Chat-bots to make Navigation Better</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/voice/recognition,/chat-bots,/navigation/2017/03/09/voice-recognition-chat-bot.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using Voice Recognition and Chat-bots to make Navigation Better" /><published>2017-03-09T01:33:52-08:00</published><updated>2017-03-09T01:33:52-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/voice/recognition,/chat-bots,/navigation/2017/03/09/voice-recognition-chat-bot</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/voice/recognition,/chat-bots,/navigation/2017/03/09/voice-recognition-chat-bot.html">&lt;p&gt;Resources for Christopher’s 2017 Esri Developer Summit Presentation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1500484083096-6a769f58a83d?ixlib=rb-0.3.5&amp;amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjEyMDd9&amp;amp;s=9b89a193a865c0f12d780284e12cd55b&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;w=634&amp;amp;q=80&quot; alt=&quot;navigation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;quot;https://github.com/MoravecLabs/VoiceNavigation&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;https://github.com/MoravecLabs/VoiceNavigation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Powerpoint: &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;quot;#&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;Using Voice Recognition and Chat-bots to make Navigation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Resources for Christopher’s 2017 Esri Developer Summit Presentation</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Building Automated Tests for Python Toolbox Tools</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/python,/testing,/automation/2017/03/08/buillding-automated-tests-python.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building Automated Tests for Python Toolbox Tools" /><published>2017-03-08T06:13:42-08:00</published><updated>2017-03-08T06:13:42-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/python,/testing,/automation/2017/03/08/buillding-automated-tests-python</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/python,/testing,/automation/2017/03/08/buillding-automated-tests-python.html">&lt;p&gt;Resources from Christopher’s 2017 Esri Developer Summit Presentation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1514428631868-a400b561ff44?ixlib=rb-0.3.5&amp;amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjEyMDd9&amp;amp;s=5f3415e4eb5f1f66b72a9733b7f598dd&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;w=1350&amp;amp;q=80&quot; alt=&quot;code&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GitHub: &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;quot;https://github.com/MoravecLabs/ArcpyTestExample&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;https://github.com/MoravecLabs/ArcpyTestExample&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PowerPoint: &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;Building Automated Tests for Python Toolbox Tools 170223a&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Resources from Christopher’s 2017 Esri Developer Summit Presentation</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Building a Better Transit App - Part 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/transit,/tech/2017/02/14/building-better-transit-app-pt-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building a Better Transit App - Part 2" /><published>2017-02-14T04:33:32-08:00</published><updated>2017-02-14T04:33:32-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/transit,/tech/2017/02/14/building-better-transit-app-pt-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/transit,/tech/2017/02/14/building-better-transit-app-pt-2.html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-working-map-with-my-location&quot;&gt;A working map, with my location!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first bit of code, I set out to get a working map and a button to press to zoom the map to my current location. I ended up spending a lot of time cleaning some of the code that I brought over from other projects, especially once I introduced StyleCop to my workflow. That took some getting used to, but now that I am starting to get the hang of it, I like it. Adding StyleCop forced me to be more honest about the organization of my code, hopefully making it better code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that done, and my code cleaned up it was time to Add the Esri SDK and Put a map on it! I ended up adding a lot of complexity to such a simple task, but this complexity should make my life much easier as the app grows, and it certainly makes the view controller pretty straight forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;#&quot; alt=&quot;screen shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;public override void ViewDidLoad()
{
    base.ViewDidLoad();

    // Create any objects and binding events.
    this.viewModel = new MainMapViewModel();
    this.viewModel.Map.SubscribePropertyChanged((oldVal, newVal) =&amp;gt;
    {
        this.MapView.Map = newVal;
    });

    // Initialize objects.
    this.viewModel.Initialize();
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This code makes use of my Atom class and a general pattern I am trying out where values are not set in the constructor of the ViewModel, instead, they are set in either Initialize or InitializeAsync depending on what my needs are.  Using the SubscribePropertyChanged method on the Atom wrapper of the Map I can put an anonymous action that always resets the MapView.Map whenever the viewModel.Map changes.  This works much the same way a one-way binding does in WPF only here I am doing it all in code.  Using an anonymous function like this provides a lot of power, essentially allowing me to handle any conversions needed in addition to listening to the event.  In a way, it is like combing the binding and value converter concepts from WPF into a single function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes my ViewModel look like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;public class MainMapViewModel : BaseViewModel
{
    /// &amp;lt;summary&amp;gt;
    /// Initializes a new instance of the &amp;lt;see cref=&quot;T:PublicTransit.MainMapViewModel&quot;/&amp;gt; class.
    /// &amp;lt;/summary&amp;gt;

    public MainMapViewModel()
    {
        this.Map = new Atom&amp;lt;Map&amp;gt;(null, this, &quot;Map&quot;);
    }

    /// &amp;lt;summary&amp;gt;
    /// Gets the map.
    /// &amp;lt;/summary&amp;gt;

    /// &amp;lt;value&amp;gt;The map.&amp;lt;/value&amp;gt;
    public Atom&amp;lt;Map&amp;gt; Map { get; private set; }

    /// &amp;lt;summary&amp;gt;
    /// Initialize this instance.
    /// &amp;lt;/summary&amp;gt;

    public void Initialize()
    {
        this.Map.Value = MapUtilities.CreateStandardMap();
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, the ViewModel contains a Property Map which is an Atom wrapper of an Esri Map object.  It gets an initial creation in the constructor but does not get a real value until the Initialize function is called.  This allows me to set up my events (binding) before the value is set.  You can’t always set the initial value to null like I have here.  If the Atom is wrapping a not nullable type like int or double you will have to set a value, but as long as the value changes in Initialize, the change events will fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may also notice that I am using a static function to generate the actual map.  I did this because I am anticipating multiple maps that will have the same or very similar data and want a central place to create them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-location&quot;&gt;But Location…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still needed to zoom the map and get a button there so that I could zoom to my current location.  Setting the initial zoom of the map was pretty easy and I settled with this to start:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;map.InitialViewpoint = new Viewpoint(45.522689, -122.678187, 4000);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I needed to add a button to the map so that I could zoom to my location and get nearby stops. My first attempt was not so cool:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;#&quot; alt=&quot;screen shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But after adding in a Material Design library I was able to get something much nicer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;#&quot; alt=&quot;screen shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s about it for this installment, next I plan on getting the actual stop locations into the map.  I added a few extra details below for those interested.  You can find this &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;quot;https://github.com/MoravecLabs/PublicTransitApp/tree/Part-2&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;Public Transit App code&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-few-details-that-i-didnt-include-within-the-main-blog&quot;&gt;A few details that I didn’t include within the main blog:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Atom&lt;/em&gt; – A small class that acts as a wrapper for any type. Once wrapped the data is set or access via the Value field. In addition, it can automatically be registered with a view model so that NotifyPropertyChanged works correctly. An Atom also has its own event subscription so that you can simply subscribe to a change. The idea is to give me a very event-driven tool that I can use within any framework. One of the issues I found while building the prototype of this app was the complexity in connecting ViewModels to Controllers in iOS when the two concepts work a bit differently. I found myself writing a lot of code, using Atoms I can reduce that code by creating “bindings” by using events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;StyleCop&lt;/em&gt; – I want this app to be readable so that I can refer back to it in the future. StyleCop seems to be a good way to keep everything formatted well. In Python, I always try to follow PEP-8 as best as I can, but I didn’t know what to use for C# until my wife, &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;quot;https://github.com/codergrl&amp;quot;&quot;&gt;@codergrl&lt;/a&gt;, told me about StyleCop!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;MaterialDesign&lt;/em&gt; – I forgot this on my main list last week, but I do want this app to be nice to look at so I’m going to try out some of the Xamarin iOS material design plugins to see what happens.  I ended up using Material Design for iOS by FPT.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A working map, with my location!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Building a Better Transit App - Part 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/transit,/tech/2017/02/05/building-better-transit-app-pt-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building a Better Transit App - Part 1" /><published>2017-02-05T14:23:35-08:00</published><updated>2017-02-05T14:23:35-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/transit,/tech/2017/02/05/building-better-transit-app-pt-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/transit,/tech/2017/02/05/building-better-transit-app-pt-1.html">&lt;p&gt;I have spent a lot of time recently learning and working with Xamarin Studio and I wanted a useful project to build to exercise my new skills.  Living in PDX I use public transportation a lot, almost every day in fact.  I am either on my bike or on the bus to and from work and most errands around town.  I am constantly frustrated by the inaccuracy of Google Maps’ transit information and the poor usability of other apps, so I am setting out to fix that.  I am building this app for myself more than anything, but I will document my process here and release the code to GitHub as I go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post serves as my scope for the project, and a place to document my goals, requirements etc.  I have already built a prototype that my wife and I have been using around town, and we both like it but it needs refinement and simplification.  For phase one of this application, my goal is to provide simple up-to-the-minute times for nearby transit stops.  This helps solve my main problem of planning when to leave to catch a bus or streetcar to get somewhere, I already know how I am going to get there the question is when.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phase 2&lt;/em&gt; will add exploration to the application.  Sometimes you need to know where a bus goes, what are the stops for that bus, etc.  With this, I want to give myself the ability to look for alternate routes that happen to be going in the direction I want to go or discover a bus route by just knowing the bus number from the stop I’m standing at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that, here are some more specific requirements, technologies, etc:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;iOS app using Xamarin Studio&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leave opportunity to add Andriod using Xamarin Studio for later&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leveraging Esri mapping technology&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Separation of “logic” and “GUI” using ViewModels&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leverage functional programming, in this case, use classes for data/models and functions for actions (where appropriate)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Experiment more with event-based programming&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Include tests at the function, model, and ViewModel level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be posting the code to GitHub in my [Public Transit App}(https://github.com/MoravecLabs/PublicTransitApp) repository while working on this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that wraps up the introduction/plan for this little project!  Off to write code!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I have spent a lot of time recently learning and working with Xamarin Studio and I wanted a useful project to build to exercise my new skills. Living in PDX I use public transportation a lot, almost every day in fact. I am either on my bike or on the bus to and from work and most errands around town. I am constantly frustrated by the inaccuracy of Google Maps’ transit information and the poor usability of other apps, so I am setting out to fix that. I am building this app for myself more than anything, but I will document my process here and release the code to GitHub as I go.</summary></entry></feed>